litscape.com 2019-07-27

# Privacy and Cookie Information

* * *

Litscape.com provides free content and services to our visitors. We do not require registration or the submission of Personally Identifiable Information (PII). The only exception is the the collection of the Internet Protocol (IP) addresses used by visitors to our website, which appears to be PII as defined within various international privacy laws, and specifically, the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR).

IP address are saved in standard log files during the routine operations of our servers for the purposes of resolving technical issues and to ensure the security and protection of our systems. Within a maximum period of 30 days, log files are removed and processed to convert the IPs to anonymous values. This process results in the permanent removal of PII from our log files, which are then used for statistical purposes and to improve our services.

Litscape.com absolutely and unconditionally will not sell, exchange or otherwise distribute PII we collect to a third-party for any reason, except as required by law.

Litscape.com uses third-parties to provide some of our services. While we do not have direct control over these providers, links to each of their respective privacy policies are included with the following descriptions of each one: 

Litscape.com uses the Content Distribution Network (CDN) services of Cloudflare Inc.  

Litscape.com includes social media links provided by AddThis Tools.  
[AddThis Privacy And Data Practices (with Data Collection And Advertising Optouts)](https://www.addthis.com/privacy/privacy-policy)

In order to keep our content and services free for our the exclusive use of our Internet visitors, Litscape.com uses advertisements placed on our website by third-party advertising partners. These advertisers may collect and maintain PII as defined in their respective Privacy and Cookie policies as linked below. Currently, visitors will see advertisements provided through Google Inc.  

Depending on the nature and locale of a transaction, Litscape.com is subject to compliance with the following relevant Privacy Legislation. Specifically, inter-provincial and most international transactions are covered under the Canadian legislation, while intra-provincial transactions (within Alberta) are covered under the Alberta legislation. For website visitors located in the EU, the GDPR applies.

[Canada: Personal Information Protection and Electronic Documents Act (S.C. 2000, c. 5)](http://laws-lois.justice.gc.ca/eng/acts/P-8.6/)

* * *

Cookies are small files stored by your web browser on your computer or mobile device. They are used to recall visitor information relevant to the operation of many -- if not most -- of the websites you visit. The cookies saved by a specific website domain, Litscape.com for example, can be recalled only by the website which saved them. While our service partners described in the Privacy Section above may set third-party cookies, Litscape.com cannot access or read the cookies they set. They, in turn, cannot access or read the cookies we set.

Personally Identifiable Information (PII) is not stored in any of the cookies used by Litscape.com.

Cookies are used on Litscape.com for the following purposes:

  * We use a unique, randomly-assigned cookie to identify each visitor in order to validate your acceptance of our cookie and privacy policies during subsequent visits, for statistical purposes, and to protect our systems from fraudulent access and abuse.
  * We use operational cookies, such as an authorization cookie and various timers to protect our word tool systems from abuse.
  * We use cookies to improve visitor experience by storing your display preferences and your last search term on as you navigate from word tool to word tool.

The cookies stored by our third-party service partners are described in detail by clicking their respective cookie or privacy policy links displayed below. These sites also provide information on how you can control whether they may collect your personal information. At this time, Litscape.com has restricted ads shown to visitors under EEA regulations (GDPR) to nonpersonalized ads only.

* * *

## Google Ads

[Set your Google Ad Preferences. Control the information Google uses to show you ads.](https://adssettings.google.com/anonymous?hl=en&sig=ACi0TCjd_Nenr6h8EqgTzWXf8EhzqwIycdvvNci_1ble9Qjta6lRak2CZD4DAXQJE537TQ-ONZROsv1tYotM0zz3XULKoRrutiioM3V2E7q5lM8q1tt3qkA&od=1)

[How Google uses information from sites or apps that use our services](https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites)

* * *

## AddThis

[AddThis Privacy And Data Practices (with Data Collection And Advertising Optouts)](https://www.addthis.com/privacy/privacy-policy)

* * *

## Cloudflare

* * *
